Jessica D. Morris

Software Engineering Associate (she/her)

Contact

<redacted>

contact@jessicamorris.dev

Ottawa, ON, Canada

in https://jessicamorris.dev

Education

Carleton University

Bachelor of Engineering,

Computer Systems with High Distinction, 2017

Key Skills

Full-Stack Development

Java

Node, React

Python

nginx/OpenResty

Scrum coaching

Golang

Profile

Hi there, I'm Jess (she/her), and I've been a software engineering associate at Atlassian for nearly two years. I've worn a variety of hats in my short tenure, but I've established myself as someone who will step up when deadlines are tight and we need to GSD (Get Stuff Done).

Professional Experience

August 2024 - Present

(remote) Ottawa, ON

Software Engineering Associate - Post-Deployment Verification at Atlassian

- Working on a Golang service that orchestrates hundreds of Docker containers for running post-deployment verification tasks, such as heartbeat monitoring and frontend testing scripts.
- Current project is decomposing the service's monorepo into independent polyrepos to speed up delivery, and enable Safe Release Management.
- Built and maintain the pipeline for sending daily data snapshots to Atlassian's datalake. I've built Databricks dashboards for measuring adoption, and for tracking down out-of-date task configurations.

November 2023 - July 2024

(remote) Ottawa, ON

Software Engineering Associate - Developer Productivity Services at Atlassian

- Maintained and administered the company's SonarQube instance.
 - Planned, tested, and rolled out two major upgrades with minimal downtime and zero data loss.
 - Automated resource management and configuration using Terraform and Ansible playbooks.
 - Communicating with hundreds of stakeholders about planned downtime and upcoming releases.
 - Writing documentation, such as rollout/rollback procedures, post-mortems for incidents, and blog posts announcing major changes.
- Collaborated across teams on a Node service for ingesting all Atlassian repository metadata and CI/CD configurations into the central datalake.
- Worked on metrics and analysis for a new Managed Builds service for standardizing CI/CD practices at Atlassian. My major project was building an 80% accurate "eligibility checker" algorithm to assess how repositories could adopt Managed Builds.
- Mentored the team's summer intern, which included:
 - Planning a 3-month project, with allowances for being behind or ahead of schedule.
 - Holding weekly one-on-ones and being available for other assistance (unblocking, code reviews, reviewing presentations).
 - Ensuring they met their milestones for the Atlassian internship program.
 - At the end of their term, they delivered two bugfixes and two minor features.

Jessica D. Morris

Software Engineering Associate (she/her)

Contact

<redacted>

contact@jessicamorris.dev

Ottawa, ON, Canada

in https://jessicamorris.dev

Awards

2019

CSE Corporate Award (Team) for Host Based Sensors program

December 2019

CSE Instant Recognition Award for ObservationDeck Top Secret-to-Protected B transfer

October 2018

automation

Team Win (HoneyNet) - GeekWeek 5

Professional Experience (continued)

December 2022 - October 2023

(remote) Ottawa, ON

Software Engineering Associate - Customer Support Technology at Atlassian

- Back-end development in Java with Spring & Spring Boot, Hibernate, GraphQL, and various tiers of caching (Caffeine, Redis) and data persistence (Postgres).
- Front-end development in React with Atlaskit elements, tests with Jest and Cypress.
- Led a rebranding project, which included representing the engineering team at stakeholder meetings, organizing and facilitating a Bug Bash to test the transition from old to new branding, and tasking the team to address bugs ahead of release day.
- Drove improvements to team culture and engineering processes, such as leading Learning Hours on application security and monthly Developer Productivity reviews.
- Diagnosed performance issues in an event-driven feature using SignalFx (for AWS Cloudwatch and custom metrics) and pgAdmin (for database performance)

December 2021 - July 2022

Ottawa, ON

Cyber Developer - Report Authoring

at Communications Security Establishment

- Implemented front-end features in Angular, such as support for multi-classification environments, and automated testing using Cypress.
- Worked with the Information Management team to pilot a use case for the Digital Vault project, automation for archiving published reports. CSE's Digital Vault will be the first fully automated digital archiving system in the Government of Canada.
- Diagnosed bugs with end users and made live corrections in the database when necessary, and wrote comprehensive bug reports.

October 2019 - November 2021

Ottawa, ON

Cyber Developer - ObservationDeck

at Canadian Centre for Cyber Security

- Developed features for ObservationDeck, an automated cyber defence reporting system for government departments.
- Designed & implemented an automation system for transferring ObservationDeck code & data across classification systems. Received an official award of recognition from management for this system.
- Implemented RESTful microservices for enriching ObservationDeck data. One of my FastAPI-based services is being actively collaborated on with a second party.
- Designed & implemented centralized authorization control and audit logging for supporting microservices using nginx and Lua scripts.
- Implemented the Scrum process for the team.